spreadshirtmedia.com 2017-08-29

# Privacy Policy | Spreadshirt

Thank you for your interest in our online offer. Protecting your privacy is important to us. Below we will explain in detail how we deal with your data. 

## 1\. Who is responsible for dealing with your data?

The responsible party for data collection, processing and usage of your personal data is sprd.net AG, Giesserstr. 27, 04229 Leipzig, Germany (hereafter referred to as “Spreadshirt”). 

If you should have any questions as to the collection, processing or usage of data and requests for information, correction, disabling or deletion of data as well as revocation of a previously given consent, please address these via email, fax or letter to: 

sprd.net AG, Giesserstr. 27, 04229 Leipzig, Deutschland   
Telefax: +49 (0)341 59 400 5499  
Email: [datenschutz@spreadshirt.net ](mailto:datenschutz@spreadshirt.net)  

## 2\. To what extent does Spreadshirt collect personal data for further processing or usage?

### Using Spreadshirt’s online offer 

You can visit our site without providing personal information. We only store access data and not personal data, even if visiting our site directly from a newsletter link. 

  * the name of your Internet service provider
  * the page from which you get directed to us
  * the name of the requested file
  * date and time of the processing request
  * amount of data transferred
  * confirmation of successful transfer of data 
  * browser type and operating system of the user 

This data is collected for the purpose of improving our offers alone, and personal data cannot be inferred from it. 

### Orders with Spreadshirt

We collect, process and use your data for the purpose of executing your order. This includes individual customer service and advice as well as processing future warranty claims. 

After expiry of the applicable tax and commercial retention periods your data will be deleted. 

In order to process your order, we need your name, address and payment data. We also need your email address so that we can confirm having dispatched your order with Spreadshirt. Your email address will be used as a means of identifying you with your user account. 

If you do not already have a user account with Spreadshirt, you can decide on registering such a password-protected account once the order is completed. Transmitting this data makes future orders possible without having to re-enter your personal information. You can also review your previous orders as well as pending orders, and you can administer your contact data and bank data. 

### Shop operators / providers of ideas 

We also collect, process and use your data in order to accomplish existing contract agreements with regard to operating Spreadshirt shops (including contracts with Premium Shop features) and / or your provision of ideas. Registering a Spreadshirt account is necessary to fulfil these contractual agreements. Spreadshirt sends you information in irregular intervals, particularly on changes with regard to its product range or service, advice on how to use Spreadshirt’s service as well as service reports. 

### Advertising and market research

Data that has been submitted to us, in particular in the process of ordering or registering customer information(signing up to newsletters via email or mail etc.) will be collected, processed and used as long as you have given your consent or statutory regulations allow for it. 

You can object to the usage of your data for the purpose of advertising and market research at the address above. 

### Establishment of contact

Establishing contact (e.g. by filing in a contact form or via email) results in the collection, processing and usage of your data for the purpose of dealing with your request as well as future inquiries. 

### Comments and submissions on the blog and forum

If you leave a comment on our blog, we collect, process and use the name and email address that you stated, although only your name that you state will be visible to other users. 

In order to view the content of the protected area of Spreadshirt’s forum or to publish comments on Spreadshirt’s forum, users need to log in with their data (user name and password) that they use to access their user account. 

We also store the user’s IP address with every blog and forum contribution.   
The data collected in the course of using the blog or forum is used for operating the blog and forum alone. Collecting this data is also necessary to ensure that we can take action in the case of users posting unlawful content (e.g. of insulting, politically inappropriate, propagandistic nature etc.). This is necessary so that we cannot be held liable for comments and submissions, and we need to make sure that we investigate such instances ourselves. 

### Comment subscription 

You can subscribe to receive messages posted on our blog and follow-up comments on the forum. For this purpose we collect, process and use your email address. You can always unsubscribe to such a subscription without having to pay anything other than the costs for your basic Internet charges. 

You can also subscribe to receive blog posts through a so-called RSS feed. When choosing this, your web browser will place a so-called ‘live bookmark’ of our blog page in your web browser, or the website data will be saved by means of a software typically used for this purpose (e.g. Microsoft Outlook). Our blog messages are automatically reloaded when starting the browser or the software used for this purpose, and they can be accessed through the browser bookmarks or the applicable software. Here, we only store access data and not personal data such as your operating ssytem type, Internet service provider, date and time of retrieval, name of access file and IP address. This data is collected for the purpose of improving our offers alone, and personal data cannot be inferred from it. You can always unsubscribe to the RSS feed by deleting the bookmark from your browser or the software that you used to open it. 

## 3\. Will my data be imparted to third parties? 

We pass on your personal data to third-parties involved in processing your order or request. This includes service providers (e.g. carriers, forwarding agents, banks) as well as third parties processing our order. In case you should choose express delivery, Spreadshirt will also communicate your telephone number to the forwarder in order to facilitate coordinating a delivery date. In this case, the data submitted may only be used for the purpose of executing the delivery. 

## 4\. Can I demand disclosure, correction, disabling and deletion of my data?

According to the German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz)you have, if the statutory conditions are met, the right to free information about your stored data and a right to rectification, blocking or erasure of data. 

## 5\. Which of my data is used for competitions.

When carrying out competitions, we use your data to give you notice in the event of you having won the competition, and, with your consent, to send you advertising. Detailed information can be found in the conditions of participation of the individual competition. 

## 6\. Do we place cookies when you visit Spreadshirt’s online offer? 

We place so-called browser cookies with our online offers. Cookies are files that allow us to store specific data relating to you on your computing device in order to exchange information between Spreadshirt’s system and your browser. Storing this information helps us create online offers for you and it makes using the platform easier for you as you don’t need to keep re-entering your information. In your browser settings you can adjust the settings for cookies, which may lead to our service becoming restricted or defunct as far as our offers are concerned. Cookies can also be deleted. 

### Session cookies

Session cookies are deleted after closing the browser. 

### Long-term cookies

We use cookies that remain on your hard-disk. For your convenience, the maximum usability period is set to a future date. When visiting Spreadshirt’s site again, your previous settings and information statements can be used and seen again by means of long-term cookies. 

### Cookies from Spreadshirt:

Spreadshirt uses cookies that do not store personal data in order to prevent any data to be associated with a person. Data collection takes place by means of pseudonymised allocation of ID numbers that are not associated with your personal data. These cookies contain information concerning the usage of our online offers such as viewings of pages or products. 

### Third-party cookies

Spreadshirt collaborates with companies to improve online offers and to make both offers and online experience more interesting. This is why we use cookies of our partner companies that are also stored on your hard-disk. Third-party cookies do not store personal data so that no information stated by customers can be associated with a person. Data collection takes place by means of pseudonymised allocation of ID numbers that are not associated with your personal data. These cookies contain information concerning the usage of our online offers such as viewings of pages or products. 

You can object to the creation of user profiles by means of pseudonyms. Please refer to possible ways to do so here: 

## 7\. What promotional measures does Spreadshirt undertake?

### Email advertising with newsletters and direct mail advertising.

If you have registered for email newsletters, your email address is used for marketing purposes up to the point in time when you unsubscribe from this service. In case you have agreed to receive direct mail, we will use your personal address data for marketing purposes until you unsubscribe from it. You can unsubscribe at any point in time without having to pay anything other than the costs for your basic Internet charges. 

### Email marketing without newsletter registration

If you did not object to the collection of your email address during checking out with an order or before, we will use it in order to send you information on products similar to those that you ordered with us in regular intervals. This notification does not function as consent from your side to usage of your email address for advertising purposes. 

### User-based advertising

Information received from users using our online offer help us create interesting and tailor-made advertising for you. Spreadshirt gleans information in a pseudonymised way from you when visiting our platform. This includes information on your computer and Internet access, operating system as well as platform, date and time of your visit or products viewed. 

In order to get information on user behaviour, cookies are stored on your computer that make identifying a pseudonymised user possible without bearing any relevance to your personal data. 

This data collection is used to carry our user-based advertising campaigns by Spreadshirt: 

  * Google, Inc. – Information on data protection with Google can be found on <http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/>
  * Criteo SA - Information on data protection with Criteo SA can be found on<http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>
  * sociomantic labs GmbH - Information on data protection with sociomantic labs GmbH can be found on <https://www.sociomantic.com/privacy/de>

If you do not wish to receive user-based advertising material, you can object to it through the following links. 

  * <http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>
  * <https://www.sociomantic.com/privacy/de>

In your browser settings you can adjust the usage restrictions for third-party cookies, which may lead to our service becoming restricted or defunct as far as our offers are concerned. Cookies can also be deleted. 

### Right of objection to the use of data for the purpose of advertising

Of course you can object to further usage of you data at any point in time - even in cases when using this data is legally permitted - by sending a simple message to us. This does not incur any costs for you other than the basic charges of your Internet provider. You can i.e. write an email to [datenschutz@spreadshirt.net,](mailto:datenschutz@spreadshirt.net) when accessing the newsletter administration in your user area, or by referring to the unsubscribe link in a newsletter that you have received. You can also address us directly, please refer to subparagraph 1 for further contact details. 

## 8\. What kind of services and content of third parties does Spreadshirt deploy when creating online offers?

For the creation of our online offer, we also use third-party content such as YouTube videos or graphics by other online providers. This is only possible if these providers (hereinafter referred to as “third-party suppliers”) are allowed to use the recipient’s IP address. Without using the IP address, the content can not be displayed in the recipient’s browser. The IP address is necessary for displaying this type of content. We always try to only use such content provided by third-party suppliers in order to deliver the content in question. We cannot, however, exert influence on whether third-party suppliers store your IP address (e.g. for statistical purposes) or not. Should we be informed about this circumstance, we will inform you. 

## 9\. Does Spreadshirt use data for web data analysis?

### Google Analytics

This online offer uses Google Analytics, a web analysis tool by Google Inc. (“Google“). Google Analytics collects and stores data in a pseudonymised way to create user profiles. These user profiles serve the purpose of analysing user behaviour, and they are used to improve our offer in order to meet the demands of our customers. Pseudonymised user profiles are not associated with the actual person behind the pseudonym without prior consent of this person to explicitly agree with this circumstance. 

Google Analytics uses cookies that are stored on your computer in order to facilitate recognition when revisiting our online offer. The information on your site visit generated by these cookies are usually transferred to and stored at a Google server in the USA. Due to the activation of IP anonymisation in combination with this offer, the IP address of users from the EU and other EEA (European Economic Area) contracting states will be shortened before being transmitted. Your IP is only transferred to a Google server in the USA in very few exceptional cases. Google adheres to the data regulations of the “US Safe Harbor” treaty, and it is registered with the “Safe Harbor” program of the US Department of Commerce. 

On behalf of the provider of this online offer, Google will use this information in order to assess how the online offer is used, to file reports on online activities and to create further offers and services depending on the internet usage and behaviour of customer. The IP address that has been transmitted by your browser is not associated with any other data by Google. Should it be required by law or should a third party process these data on behalf of Google, Google may pass on this information to third parties. 

You can prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting the settings of your browser software; we need to point out that this may lead to an inhibition of the full functionality of our online offer. In addition to this, you can prevent the collection of cookie generated information (incl. your IP address) for the purpose of using the online offer as well as further processing this data by Google, if you download and install the browser plug-in available here: ([https://tools.google.com](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de)

You can prevent Google Analytics from retrieving your data by clicking on the following button. An opt-out cookie will be placed to prevent future data recording when visiting this online offer: 

You can find more information on user terms and conditions here: [ http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html) and [http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview](http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html). 

We need to point out that the website Google Analytics has been extended by the code “gat._anonymizeIp();“ to make anonymous gathering of IP address data (so called IP masking) possible by means of Google analytics. 

### Further analytical tools

Our online offer uses analysis tools to collect and store data in order to create user profiles in a pseudonymised way. These user profiles serve the purpose of analysing user behaviour, and they are used to improve our offer so that we can meet the demands of our customers. Cookies may be used for this purpose. Pseudonymised user profiles are not associated with the actual person behind the pseudonym without prior consent of this person to explicitly agree with this circumstance. You can prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting the settings of your browser software; we need to point out that this may lead to an inhibition of the full functionality of our online offer. Spreadshirt uses the following analytic tools: 

Omniture and AdLens, web analysis tools by Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited, offers more information of data protection on [http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy.html) and [http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/analytics](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/analytics.html). You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by Adobe if you unsubscribe on[http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out.html). 

Optimizely is a web analysis tool by Optimizely Inc. – please find more information on matters of data protection on <https://www.optimizely.com/privacy>. You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by Optimizely if you unsubscribe on <https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out>. 

Crazyegg is a web analysis tool by Crazyegg Inc. – please find more information on matters of data protection on <http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy>. You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by Crazyegg if you unsubscribe on <http://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out>. 

Hotjar is a web analysis tool by Hotjar, Ltd. – please find more information on matters of data protection on <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>. You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by Hotjar if you unsubscribe via the contact form on <https://www.hotjar.com/contact>. 

Our website may also use a website recording service which may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. Data collected by this service is used to improve our website usability. The information collected is stored and is used for aggregated and statistical reporting, and is not shared with anybody else.

## 10\. Does Spreadshirt use social plug-ins?

### Facebook

Our online offer makes use of so called social plug-ins of the social network provider Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. The plug-ins are labelled with the Facebook logo or “like button”. Please refer to an overview of our plugins on <http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>. 

If a user accesses our online portal containing such a plug-in, a direct connection between browser and user gets established through the Facebook server. In doing so, Facebook receives information that the user accessed a specific page of our online offer. In case the user is already registered with Facebook, Facebook is able to associate the site view with the user account as long as the user is logged in to Facebook while accessing our online offer. If a user interacts with a plug-in, e.g. by using the “like button” or leaves a comment while being logged into Facebook and simultaneously accessing our online offer, Facebook receives information on this circumstance and records it. 

It needs to be pointed out that we have no information with regard to the content of the data and further usage of the data that Facebook receives. More information on the data protection of Facebook can be found on <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. 

If you want to prevent this kind of data association and usage, you need to log out of your Facebook account before accessing our online offer. 

### Pinterest

Our online offer also includes social plug-ins by Pinterest, Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA 94301 USA. The plug-ins are labelled with the “Pin it” button. The button icon makes it possible to share a page or a design that is part of our online offer with Pinterest. 

If a user accesses our online portal containing such a plug-in, a direct connection between browser and user gets established through the Pinterest server. In doing so, Pinterest receives information that the user accessed a specific page of our online offer. If a user clicks the “Pin it” button while being logged in with his Pinterest account, he can link up the our offer viewed online to his Pinterest profile. In doing so, Pinterest can associate our online offer with the user account at Pinterest. 

It needs to be pointed out that we have no information with regard to the content of the data and further usage of the data that Pinterest receives. More information on the data protection of Pinterest can be found on <http://about.pinterest.com/privacy>. 

If you want to prevent this kind of data association and usage, you need to log out of your Pinterest account before accessing our online offer. 

### Addthis

Our online offer also includes social plug-ins by Addthis, provided by Clearspring Technologies, Inc. Addthis is a bookmark provider, helping to set bookmarks and communicating websites (e.g. through Pinterest). On completion of the order with Spreadshirt, the plug-in enables the user to share what has just been purchased by means of social online networks or email. Addthis uses cookies. Data generated here (e.g. time of access or browser language) are submitted to the USA and processed by Clearspring Technologies, Inc. 

Please find more information on data processing and data protection of Clearspring Technologies, Inc. on <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy>. This website contains information on the data type used for further processing as well as their intended use. We do not process these data. You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by unsubscribing on <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>. 

###  ShareThis 

Our Internet presence uses so-called Social Plugin ShareThis by the provider ShareThis, Inc. in order to communicate websites in a straightforward way (e.g. via email, Facebook, Pinterest, Twitter etc.). In combination with this service, ShareThis places cookies. Data generated here (e.g. time of access or browser language) are submitted to the USA and processed by ShareThis Inc. 

You can find ShareThis Inc.’s privacy policy on [http://www.sharethis.com/legal/privacy/"](http://www.sharethis.com/legal/privacy/#sthash.qAtj3M1f.dpbs). This website contains information on the data type used for further processing as well as their intended use. We do not process these data. You can object to the collection, storage and usage of data for future activities by unsubscribing on [http://www.sharethis.com/legal/privacy/"](http://www.sharethis.com/legal/privacy/#sthash.qAtj3M1f.dpbs). 

## 11\. Is your data safe?

Your personal data as well as your payment data is encrypted when being submitted online. We adopt technical and organisational measures to safeguard our online offer from leakage, damage, access and modification as well as unwanted sharing of your data by unauthorised persons. Accessing your user account is only possible upon entering your password. You should always treat your log-in data confidentially and close the browser window after finishing your communication, particularly when using a computer that others have access to as well. 

## 12\. Which declarations of consent apply to Spreadshirt’s online offers?

The following declaration(s) of consent have been given to Spreadshirt, and we have put these on record. The German Teleservices Act makes it obligatory for us to make declarations of consent available to be viewed. We need to point out that you can always revoke your declarations of consent at any time in the future. 

**Subscribe to Newsletter**  
[Field for entering your email addresse] [register]  
Subscribe to the Spreadshirt newsletter. What’s your benefit?  
(you can always unsubscribe)  

**Subscribe to Newsletter**  
[Field for entering your email addresse] [register]  
Data protection at Spreadshirt  
Spreadshirt only uses your email address to send you info emails. Unsubscribing from the newsletter is possible at all times 

**Customer Newsletters** The best Marketplace products and current promotions from Spreadshirt’s product range - every week, fresh in your email inbox. You can always unsubscribe.  
[Button:] Sign up 

**Shop Partner Newsletter** We keep you up-to-date on special campaigns, new features and impart tips and tricks to improve your shop sales. This newsletter gets sent out about once a month. You can always unsubscribe.  
[Button:] Sign up
